■
本字幕首发于字幕组网站
www.ZiMuZu.tv 欢迎交流
翻译  Vilna  小酸奶  杏仁斯嘉丽
翻译  阿飘  Michael  小肚腩
校对  灰灰是菇凉  法顾  何方云
时间轴   葵小树  西·查
后期&总监  灰灰是菇凉
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:  ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
以后就是编号01800了
Chow at 01800.
别拘束  小孩
Make yourself at home, son.
一级谋杀 第二季 第五集
瞧
Voila.
这算不上是营养早餐吧
Not exactly the breakfast of champions.
你以前很爱吃这些啊
You used to love those things.
那时候我还小  现在我都算是少女了  妈
When I was a kid. I'm almost a teenager, mom.
你才十一岁
Um, you're 11.
我在考虑当个素食者
I'm thinking about going vegan.
是吗  拭目以待
Oh, yeah? Well, we'll see.
天哪
Oh, my God.
你说得没错  确实很恶心
Ew, you're right. They are gross.
这周晚些时候我能去玛雅家过夜吗
Can I sleep over at Maya's later this week?
麦肯纳过生日  她要办个睡衣派对
It's Mackenna's birthday, and she's having a slumber party.
是有几个哥哥那个玛雅吗
Is Maya the one with the brothers?
不行  你知道我对她的看法
No. You know how I feel about her.
你甚至都不认识她
You don't even know her.
别这样对我
Don't do this to me.
露易丝  你这是怎么了
Louise, what's going on with you?
没什么
Nothing.
再见
Goodbye.
突发新闻
Breaking news.
本台旧金山分部为你带来
We go live now to our affiliate in San Francisco
警察局长托马斯·赫尔南德斯
as police chief Thomas Hernandez
首次公开发言的现场报道
makes his first public statement.
鉴于此次校车屠杀
In light of the school-bus massacre
以及枪击事件对这座城市带来的伤害
and shooting rampage perpetrated against this city...
-你迟到了  -是啊
- You're late. - Yeah. No shit.
没事吧
All good?
青春期  真够折磨人的
Oh, adolescence -- it's a bitch.
这些嫌犯是如何组织和实施这次犯罪
...How these suspects organized and executed this crime.
这样的事  决不能发生第二次
This...can never happen again.
泰瑞
Terry.
听着  我们还要把事实隐藏多久
Listen, how long do we have to hold on to the truth here?
委员会又不会给我们发奖状
That commission ain't giving out commendations.
如果局长发现他的公开发言
If the chief finds out he went on the record
与事实不符  他就会认为是我们
with the wrong story, he'll claim we withheld
隐瞒了这次警察内部的案子
information about a cop-on-cop crime
然后把我们扔到公车底下
and throw our asses under the bus --
校车底下
the school bus.
我不明白  为什么我们不干脆告诉库图
I don't get it. Why don't we just tell Koto
是凯勒布杀了沃尔特  以免事态继续恶化
that Kaleb killed Walt and nip it in the bud?
这能一定程度解释他的自杀  对吧
It's a partial explanation for the suicide, right?
他也在问这件事
And he's asking about it.
我会告诉库图的  好吗
I'm gonna tell Koto. All right?
我明天去跟卡勒布的妈妈聊聊
I'm gonna speak with Kaleb's mother tomorrow,
看她对他的自杀有什么看法
see what she thinks about his suicide
在她发现她的儿子杀了拍档之前
before she finds out her son killed his own partner,
好吗
all right?
然后我们就告诉副队
Then we'll tell the lieutenant.
-好的  -就这样
- Yes. - All right?
泰瑞  我们得走了
Hey, Terry, we, uh -- we got to go.
我们要迟到了
We're gonna be late for that thing.
-回见  -回见
- Later. - Yep.
这段极为难熬的时光
...extremely trying time.
沃尔特·马丁的家人以及受害者
The families of Walt Martin and the victims of...
我得想设法让我俩脱身
I had to get us out of there.
了解
Oh, okay.
第一晚
First night.
有睡着吗
Did you get any sleep?
没有
No.
一整晚都很冷
I was freezing all night.
还有一些声音
There were all these sounds, too --
脚步声  开门声  什么声音都听得到
footsteps, doors -- I mean, you can hear everything.
可却什么都看不到
You can't see any of it, though.
什么都看不到
Um, you can't -- can't see anything.
你应该有毯子  我保证会给你毯子
You should have blankets. I'll make sure you get some.
达斯汀  介意跟我聊聊你的童年吗
Dustin, do you mind if I ask you about your childhood?
不介意
I don't care.
你印象中有受过伤吗  小的时候
Do you remember getting hurt when you were young?
我
I, um...
我六岁那年手臂骨折过
I, uh, broke my arm when I was 6.
我在你的医疗记录里看到了
I saw that in your medical records.
看起来伤得很严重
It looks like it was pretty bad.
是的  就只是
Yeah, it was just, um...
在我叔叔的机械修理店发生的一个意外
an accident at my uncle's machine shop.
具体是怎么发生的
What happened, exactly?
我  我不记得了
I don't, um -- I don't remember.
一点都不记得吗
At all?
一点都不记得
At all. Um...
关于那场意外
I mean, I don't -- I don't remember
或是去医院  我都不记得
the accident or going to the hospital...
或者其他任何细节
or any of it.
能不能不问了
Can we not do this?
我不是很想回答问题
I don't feel like answering questions.
-你想问什么问题吗  -是的
- You want to ask some? - Yeah.
他们会判我死刑吗
Are they going for the death penalty?
是  有这个可能
It's possible, yes.
好吧  那我想认罪
All right, well, I want to plead guilty.
等等  不是这样的
Wait a minute. That's...not how it works.
州法律有附加特殊情况
The state attaches special circumstances.
你不能直接认罪
You don't just plead guilty.
为什么
Why not?
在没有审查这个案子的情况之前
The court is not inclined to let you make that kind of emotional decision
法庭是不会允许你做出这样情绪化的决定的
without first examining the facts of the case.
审判过程能让大家明白
A trial helps everybody understand
事件的经过和起因
what happened and why.
如果直接就能认罪的话我就不用在这了
I wouldn't be doing my job if we simply pled guilty.
我并没有求你救我的命
I-I didn't ask you to save my life.
但你的命值得我救  达斯汀
But your life is worth saving, Dustin.
胡说
Bullshit!
没事
Okay, it's...
听着  最好的情况就是
I mean, look, best-case scenario, I'm...
我在这盯着这些墙看五十年
staring at walls for the next 50 years.
那有什么意义吗
How's that worth anything?
每个人的生命都是有意义的
Because every human being's life is worth something.
我还不了解你
I haven't gotten to know you yet,
但我知道  你不只是一个校车上的杀人犯
but I know that you're much more than what you did on that bus.
我在校车上做的事
What I did on that bus...
可能是我人生中唯一做对的事
...was just about the only thing I got right in my life.
你的人生才刚刚开始  年轻人
Your life has just begun, young man.
我本该在死在格林大道的
I was supposed to die on Green Street.
一切本该那时就结束的
It was supposed to be over.
但事情还没有结束
But it's not over.
也不会这么快就结束
And it's not gonna be over anytime soon.
即使我们败诉  你被判了死刑
Even if we lose a trial and you're sentenced to death,
未来二十年里
you're gonna spend the next 20 years
你将在死囚牢房里等待这一切结束
waiting out appeals on death row.
无论你喜欢与否
Like it or not,
你都必须意识到  你是有未来可言的
you have to consider the fact that you do have a future.
你没必要整天盯着墙壁发呆
You don't have to spend your time staring at walls.
你可以继续去读书
You can continue your education.
我不想继续读书
I don't want to continue my education.
你要是想活着熬过这段监狱生活
The only way you're gonna survive your incarceration
就只能把心思放到正道上来
is by putting your mind to good use.
我想不去想那些东西
I want to get out of my mind.
我想离开这个世界
I want to get out of this world.
你为什么不能终结这一切呢
Why can't you just end this?
我不想受审
I don't want a trial.
秘密中的秘密
A secret on a secret.
我小时候特别喜欢这种东西
I used to love this stuff when I was a kid.
但现在我只是倍感煎熬
Now it just eats at me.
好吧  我们现在得着手处理
All right, we got to get our heads
第二件秘密了  谁杀了凯勒布
on this second secret -- who killed Kaleb?
你觉得有没有可能
Do you think there's any chance,
有那么一丝可能性不是警察干的
any possibility, that it wasn't a cop?
没有强行闯入和搏斗的痕迹
No forced entry, no sign of a struggle.
会不会是家人
Could've been family, right?
家人  或者朋友
A family member? A friend?
谁会烧灼子弹伤口
What type of a cat uses a blowtorch
伪装成自杀啊
on a bullet wound to fake a suicide?
肯定是有法医学基础的人
That's some real forensic-type shit.
肯定是个警察
It's got to be a cop.
你认为凯勒布的死和沃特的死有关吗
You think Kaleb's murder was linked to Walt's?
我是说  两名搭档
I mean, two partners...
在几天之内相继被害
killed, you know, within a matter of days of each other.
如果没有关联的话也太巧了吧
I'd say, yeah, hell of a coincidence if it wasn't.
我们还不能确定沃特是不是被人谋杀的吧
We don't even know if Walt was murdered, right?
我是说  有可能只是误伤
I mean, it could've just as easily been friendly fire,
而他因为罪恶感太深了所以撒了谎
and he lied about it because of the guilt.
又或者他可能根本没有意识到
Or maybe he didn't even realize
那子弹是从他的枪里出来的
that the bullet came from his gun.
不  他离得...离得非常近
No, he was pretty -- he was pretty close.
可能是想分散他的注意力
Could've been a perfect diversion.
你懂吗
You know?
你也看到隧道中的情况了
You saw how it was in those tunnels.
如果有关联
Well, if it was connected,
你觉得是某种警察内部的腐败勾结吗
do you think it was some kind of cop-on-cop conspiracy?
让我们假设局里某个内奸
All right, let's say someone on the force
贿赂凯勒布让他杀了沃特
bribes Kaleb to kill Walt.
凯勒布找到机会  就照做了
Kaleb finds the opportunity, he does the deed,
当他去回报时  没拿到钱
and then when he reports back, instead of the money,
反而挨了一枪
he gets a bullet.
凯勒布用他自己的枪杀了沃特
Kaleb used his own gun to kill Walt,
这计划不太周密
so not much of a plan.
-你觉得不是这样吗  -对
- You don't think so? - No.
没人看到凯勒布扣动扳机
Look, nobody saw Kaleb pull the trigger,
所以可能是误伤  也可能是故意的
so it could be friendly, it could be deliberate.
而且当时在场的所有警察
And all those cops that were down there...
没人提到他的名字
No one brought up his name.
所有审讯中  没有提到过凯勒布的名字
No one brought up Kaleb's name in any of those interviews.
他完全可以洗脱杀害沃特的罪名
So if he wanted to get away with killing Walt, he could've.
如果沃特还没死的话
If Walt wasn't already dead.
好吧
All right.
我们先从办公室里的人查起
We'll clear everybody in our room,
然后再慢慢展开调查
and then we'll move up from there.
你相信我吗
You trust me?
我相信你
Yeah, I trust you.
太美了
It's so beautiful.
有时候我都忘了这就是我生活的地方
Sometimes I forget I actually live here.
家
Home.
走进来见不到沃特和凯勒布  大家都很难过
It's hard to walk in this room and not see Walt and Kaleb.
我们...我们失去了两名兄弟
Uh, we, uh, -- we lost two brothers.
我们要做好该做的事  安顿好他们的家人
Let's do the right thing and check up on their families,
帮他们挺过去  好吗
make sure they're holding up, all right?
纳瓦罗去哪了
Uh, hey, where's, uh -- where's Navarro?
比克斯比舞蹈俱乐部
Bixby's dance studio.
他...
H-he's, uh --
他早上有华尔兹课  长官
He's got a morning waltz class, sir.
这周末是他女儿的成人礼
His -- his daughter's quinceanera is this Sunday.
知道了  行吧  默克
Got it. All right, uh, Molk,
你到时候跟纳瓦罗通报一下最新进展
I'll let you catch Navarro up to speed.
有没有人知道为什么沃特那起案子的
Does anyone know what is taking ballistics so long
弹道学报告要花这么久
on the bullet that killed Walt?
我不知道  不过...我会问问韦斯利的
I don't know, but, uh, I'll ask Wesley.
还有凯勒布的自杀
And Kaleb's suicide --
除了法医报告外还有别的东西吗
We got something more than just the M.E.'s report?
我们还在努力  一两天后也许就会有发现
Uh, we're still working on it. Probably another day or two.
好的
All right.
听着  我不是那种
Listen, uh, I'm not the type
会花大心思在媒体发布会上的人
to pay too much attention to press conferences,
但是我们手上有一大堆悬案
but we've got a record number of open cases
这座城市还处于创伤之中  指望着我们呢
and a city in PTSD staring at us.
所以咱们要埋头苦干  加倍努力
So let's keep our heads down, redouble our efforts.
等我们做出了一些突破
When we get a couple of wins here,
一切都会回归原样
things will settle back down.
好  继续努力吧
All right. Let's get to it.
好
All right.
-欢迎回来  -是啊
- Welcome back. - Yeah.
韦拉克鲁斯  等等
Veracruz, hold up.
你好  克里奥拉指挥官
Uh, uh, hi, Commander Criolla.
我知道你一直在深入调查苏格·凯斯格特的事
I know you've been deep into Suger Cascade.
不知怎的  你的手下都暴露了
Somehow, your crew got made.
我这里有能帮你
I got something that might put you
再潜回去的东西
right back into the middle of things.
最近有个大麻温室要开了
A grow-house hit's about to go down.
这是地址和时间
That's the address and the time.
我一个在电力公司有关系的线人给我的
I got it from a C.I. Who's got a connect in the power company.
好的  谢了
Yeah, thanks.
现在科尔布队长走了  你怎么样
So, how you doing now that, uh, Captain Kolb is gone?
一切都回到正轨上了
Trains are on the rails.
我们会有新的上司吗
We getting a new boss?
马上就有了  所以别惹什么麻烦  孩子
Soon. So keep your nose clean, kid.
-给  女士  -谢谢
- Here you go, ma'am. - Thanks.
瞧瞧你  今天气色不错嘛  姑娘
Look at you. Lookin' good today, girl.
真的吗  谢了
Really? Hmm. Thanks.
你查到了些什么
So, what you got?
费尔利和希门尼斯当时在法庭上
All right, so, Fairley and Jimenez were in court,
默克在押送罪犯
and Molk was processing a prisoner.
你呢
You?
杜利  王  乔丹和
Phone records clear Dooley,
麦卡琴盖尔的通话记录都没问题
Uh, Wong, Jordan, and McCutcheon.
所以现在只剩纳瓦罗和小麦
So now all we have left is Navarro and Junior.
应该不会太难
That shouldn't be too bad.
纳瓦罗交给我  你去搞定我弟弟
I'll take Navarro, You take my brother?
不  小麦交给你
Nah, you should clear Junior.
我们必须得谈到凯勒布的死
Since we have to talk around Kaleb's murder,
你需要花的时间可能只有我的一半  所以...
it would probably take you half the time it takes me, so...
要去盘问我自己的弟弟已经够糟的了
Ugh. It's bad enough having to investigate my brother.
现在我还得跟他撒谎
Now I have to actually lie to him, too?
只是在不引起他的警觉的情况下
Nah, just a find a way to his alibi
找出他的不在场证明
without causing alarm.
我们得填一份报告  然后向库图汇报
We'll file a report, and then we'll loop Koto in.
然后我们得调查这栋楼里的每个警察
And then we have to investigate every cop in this building.
-对  -真棒
- Yes. - Great.
你好  警官
Hey, what you doin', jura?
克里斯托巴尔
Cristobal.
欢迎回来  兄弟
Welcome back, hermano.
谢谢
Thank you.
你饿吗
Hey, hey, you hungry?
我想吃巴西烤肉自助可想了几个月了
'Cause I been dreamin' about Fogo de Chao for months,
哥们  可以敞开了吃那种
Bro. All you can eat.
今晚不行  我们要在家来个家庭聚餐
Hey, not tonight. We're having a family dinner at the house.
玛塞拉一整天都在给你准备大餐
Marciella's been cooking up a feast for you all day, homey.
对她这种人可没法说不  是吧
She ain't a woman to say no to, right?
-说得对  -对
- Verdad. - That's right.
伙计
Oh, man.
听着  在你振作起来之前
Hey, listen, um, you stay with us
都跟我们待在一起  懂吗
until you get back on your feet, understand?
这对我意义重大  哥们
Oh. Means a lot, bro,
但  玛塞拉会同意吗
but, uh, is -- is Marciella cool with that?
只要你别惹麻烦就行
As long as you stay out of trouble.
另外  要是你和你朋友们待在这
Besides, if you stay here with your friends,
你这周末就能回到佩利肯湾监狱去
be back at Pelican Bay by the end of the week.
伙计  我可已经改过自新了
Man, I'm rehabilitated, homey.
圣人克里斯托巴尔  我可是好人
Santo Cristobal! I'm good!
圣人你个头  上车吧
Santo, my ass. Get in the car.
我唯一承认的圣人是圣诞老人
The only Santo I see is "Santo" Claus.
该死  你究竟是怎么在佩利肯湾监狱
Damn! How the hell do you put on weight
-长胖的  -你闭嘴吧
- at Pelican Bay? - Shut up, man.
-你闭嘴吧  -冷静下  哥们
- Shut up, man. - Chill out, bro.
我总归是你哥  蠢货
I'm still your big brother, fool.
看看是谁大驾光临
Look what the cat dragged in.
你还在忙活这破玩意儿
You still working on this piece of shit?
还记得我们在去优胜美地[国家公园]的
Remember when we were all crammed in that front seat
漫漫长路上挤在前座里吗
on those long-ass rides to Yosemite?
我只记得我们去看酋长石
I just remember you puking up on dad
过隧道的时候  你吐在了爸爸身上
when we came through the tunnel going to El Capitan.
所以我才先把汽车内饰换掉
That's why the upholstery was the first thing I replaced.
你这么早就开始喝酒了
Wow. You're hitting the bottle early, huh?
我今天放假
It's my day off.
一小时后  切尔西和她的一年级同学们
And in about an hour, Chelsea and all of her grade-one class
要来这儿办个茶会
are gonna be here for a little tea party.
现在喝鸡尾酒再合适不过了
It's the perfect time for a cocktail.
最近你经历了不少事情吧
Well, there's been a lot of that lately for you, though, huh?
你在监视我
You keeping tabs on me?
没有  只是观察而已
No, I'm not. Just an observation.
那天你在我家喝醉了
You drank at my house the other day.
只是在我回家之前做好准备而已
Just softening the landing before I go home.
那沃尔特的葬礼上呢
What about Walt's funeral?
很明显  你喝醉了
I mean, you were clearly... drunk.
我从你的口气能闻出来  酒气熏天
I smelled it on your breath. You reeked of it.
别说了  行吗
Just -- just stop, okay?
你以为我是唯一一个注意到的吗  小麦
Do you think I'm the only one who notices, Junior?
太丢人了
I mean, it's pretty embarrassing.
你是一大早就喝酒
So, what -- were you drinking in the morning,
还是中午狂饮  还是
or did you go off on a bender at lunch, or what --
你别管我的事
You need to back off.
沃尔特的葬礼那天早晨你在哪
Where were you that morning of Walt's funeral?
你在干什么  你在跟谁喝酒
What were you doing? Who were you drinking with?
希尔蒂
Oh, Hildy.
因为你嫁了个醉鬼
Just because you were married to a drunk
也不意味着你有权利到这儿来
doesn't give you the right to come over here
盘问我做了什么  去了哪里
and grill me on what I do and where I go.
-你明白吗  -明白
- You understand me? - Yeah.
我生活中的破事已经够多的了
Yeah, I got enough bullshit in my life.
希尔蒂
Hi, Hildy.
-我好像听见有人来了  -玛丽
- Thought I heard someone. - Hey, Mary.
你来这儿参加读书会
You here for book club?
不  我今晚参加不了
No, um, I'm actually not gonna be able to do it tonight.
好吧
Okay.
我弟弟没事吧
Hey, um, i-is my brother okay?
泰瑞
Hey, Terry.
听着  你参加这个成人礼吗
Listen, are you going to this quinceanera?
-嗯  打算去的  -好的
- Uh, that's the plan, yeah. - Yeah, great.
听好  我整理了一份
Okay, listen, so, I've put together a list
相关的常见问题  人们会问我
of relevant FAQs. People are gonna ask me
要穿什么  带什么礼物
what to wear, you know, to bring,
需不需要跳舞
do they have to dance.
纳瓦罗...
And, I mean, Navarro is...
-他简直疯了  -对
- He's going out of his mind. - Yeah.
顺便问一句  你见过他吗
Have you seen him, by the way?
大概一小时前见过  后来他家屠夫打来
Uh, about an hour ago, and then the butcher called --
说是猪肉出了什么问题
some kind of crisis with the pork.
好的  我过会儿再跟他谈
All right, I'll, uh, catch up with him later.
-祝你好运  -不  这是给你的
- Good luck with this. - No, that's -- that's for you.
请问有什么能为你效劳的
Can I help you?
阿莉莎
Alyssa.
你怎么进来的
H-how did you get in here?
信不信由你
Well, belive it or not,
我有随意进出地方的技能
I have a knack for getting in places.
这技能可真是...
That could be, uh...
挺有用的
really come in handy.
对
Yeah, well, um,
你说过  如果我想起来
you told me that I should get in touch with you
关于舞者莎拉的事  就联系你
if I remembered anything about that dancer, Sarah.
对
Yeah.
对  请坐吧
Right. Here. Uh --
她告诉我  她和她丈夫关系不是很好
Well, she -- she told me that she wasn't into her husband.
她已经完全不爱他了
Like -- like, she was totally over the guy.
你已经告诉过我们这件事了
Yeah, y-you know, you actually already told us that.
我说过吗
Oh. Oh, I did?
对  但没事的
Yeah. But, I mean, it's okay.
调查结束了
I mean, the investigation's closed.
她给她丈夫打了电话  莎拉还活着
She's called her husband. Sarah's alive,
听起来她没事
and it sounds like she's doing just fine.
-非常感谢你  -真的吗
- Thank you very much. - Really? Wow.
那真是太好了
That's -- that's great.
除非你是她丈夫
Unless you're her husband.
她留了条语音结束了他们的关系
She -- she left a voicemail ending it.
可怜人
Poor guy.
是啊
Yeah.
怎么了
Hey. What is it?
没...
No, um...
我
I...
我只是
I just, uh --
我刚刚跟一个朋友打了一架...
I got into a fight with a friend just now and, uh...
也不算是朋友吧  我也搞不清楚
Well, not really a friend, and I-I don't know.
突然我想到了你
All of a sudden, I-I started thinking about you
还有...
and...
...你的友善
...how nice you were.
天呐  太尴尬了
Oh, God. This is so embarrassing.
我真是蠢透了
I'm such an idiot.
不...不好意思
I-I'm -- I'm sorry.
很抱歉我浪费了你的时间
I'm really sorry to have wasted your time.
不不不  等等  等一下
No, no, no. Wait, wait.
你没有在浪费我的时间
You're not wasting my time.
我发誓  这是我今天最开心的时刻
I promise you this is the best part of my day.
你...你搞定小麦了没
Did you, uh, get things squared away with Junior?
没  还没有  怎么了
No, not yet. What's that?
沃尔特的弹道分析报告出来了
It's Walt's ballistic report.
我拦住了韦斯利
I intercepted Wesley.
我决定要亲手交过去
Decided I'd, uh, hand-deliver it myself.
然后和库图说什么
And tell Koto what?
如报告所示  凯勒布杀了沃尔特
Kaleb killed Walt, just like the report says.
那报告上没有的呢
And what about what the report doesn't say?
我们得先肃清凶案组  计划如此
Well, we should clear homicide. That's the plan, right?
但愿你清楚自己在做什么
I hope you know what you're doing.
坚持下去就是胜利
Fake it till you make it.
好  谢谢你  爸爸
Yes. Thank you, dad.
我会的
I will.
嗯
Yeah.
我会的
Uh, I will.
我得挂电话了
Hey, listen. I got to go.
晚点打给你  好吗
I-I'll call you later, all right?
再见
Bye.
那个...
Hey, the, uh...
弹道分析报告出来了
ballistics report came in.
总算啊
Finally.
也真够久的
Took them long enough.
是啊  但你会宁愿它不出来的
Yeah, you don't want it, though.
凯勒布自杀是有原因的
There's a reason why Kaleb committed suicide.
根据弹道报告  是他杀了沃尔特
According to ballistics, he killed Walt.
畏罪自杀
Murder-suicide...
居然发生在凶案组内部
In the homicide unit?
天呐  泰瑞  我们完全没有喘息的机会
Jesus christ, Terry. We can't catch a break.
是啊  至少不算复杂
Yeah. Well, at least it's tidy.
你知道的  还可能...更糟糕
You know, it could, uh -- could be worse.
就算我们不采取行动  这消息也会泄露出去
Look, this is gonna leak if we don't get out in front of it.
你是支持我的吧
You're with me, right?
当然
Of course.
没错
That's correct.
根据弹道分析结果
Due to the ballistics results,
我们将沃尔特·马丁的死因重新定为
we are reclassifying the death of Walt Martin to friendly fire,
在执勤过程中发生的误杀
killed in the line of duty.
致命的那颗子弹
The bullet that ended his life
来自他的搭档凯勒布·皮特的配枪
came from the gun of his partner, Kaleb Peat,
随后  在这份调查结果
who subsequently took his own life
出来之前  他自尽了
before any of this information came to light.
警督
皮特·凯勒布
泰瑞
Hey, Terry.
库图  你吓死我了
Koto, you scared me.
有什么需要吗
You need something?
我...我把这个落下了
I, uh -- I just left this behind.
对  但愿你不介意
Yeah. Hope you don't mind.
不  当然不了
No, of course not.
我还想着要还给你呢
I, uh, been meaning to return it.
是啊  我想你应该没有"享受"过
Yeah, I guess, uh, you never had the pleasure of your dad
事无巨细都逃不过爸爸法眼的待遇吧
micromanaging every aspect of your life, did you?
我只有这个  所以在我心目中
Ha. Well, all I had was this, so in my head,
他...他真的很完美
he was, uh -- he was pretty perfect.
好了  兄弟  谢了
All right, man. Thanks.
好
All right.
多克·维克瑞餐馆
怎么了
What's the matter?
我不知道  你看看我是不是想多了
Ohh, I don't know. You got to check me here, okay?
我想要排除小麦的嫌疑
So, I tried to cross Junior's name off the list of suspects,
但排除不了
and I can't.
没有电话记录
No phone records.
他没有打卡  他...没有不在场证明
He never clocked in. He's -- he's got no alibi.
-这样  -也许是我还没找到不在场证明吧
- All right.  - So I probably just haven't found it yet, right?
或许  也许吧
Maybe. Maybe.
然后我去他家  跟他谈天说地
And then I went to his house to talk to him about everything,
而他当时喝醉了  非常非常抵触
and he was drunk, and he was super, super defensive.
然后我...
And then I --
怎么
What?
他车库里有个喷灯
There was a blowtorch in his garage.
不过  喷灯这东西人人都有的吧
But, I mean, everybody has a blowtorch, right?
我看未必吧
Well, I don't know about that.
拜托告诉我  是我疯了
Please tell me that I'm crazy.
拜托告诉我  我弟弟没有杀凯勒布
Please tell me that my brother did not kill Kaleb.
你先看看那个
You need to check that out.
那是...凯勒布的人事档案
That's, uh, Kaleb's personnel file.
我从库图那里拿来的
I got it from Koto.
-好  -而且  显然
- All right. - And, uh, apparently,
小麦和凯勒布以前在风化组共事过
Junior and Kaleb worked Vice together back in the day.
里面有份事故报告
There's an incident report.
报告了写了些什么
Well, what's it say?
他们在猎人角的时候
That they got into some boxing match
一起调查某场拳击赛
back in the day at Hunters Point.
有个线人给他们俩提供线索
They were sharing an informant.
小麦指控凯勒布从背后刺杀该线人
Junior accused Kaleb of, uh, stabbing him in the back
诸如此类的...我也不清楚
or something like that -- I don't know.
我从来没听说过
I never heard anything about it.
小麦现在在哪里
Where's Junior now?
玛丽说他晚上开车去东湾了
Uh, Mary said he drove to East Bay for the night.
等他一回来  我们得拘押他  希尔蒂
Uh, we're gonna have to corner him when he gets back, Hildy.
我明白
I know.
我要喝一杯  你要喝一杯吗
I need a drink. You want to go get a drink?
我最不想干的就是喝酒了
That's the last thing I need.
不过还是谢了
Thanks, though.
-那好  -好
- All right. - All right.
那我先走了
I'm gonna go, then.
-路上小心  -好  你也是
- Be careful. - Yep. You, too.
这是怎么回事
Hey, what's this?
这是就算千难万险也要吃的家庭聚餐
This is a family dinner, come hell or high water.
-你能抽时间吃一下吗  -当然了
- Can you manage? - Of course.
好  这真是个惊喜
Okay. This is a nice surprise. Mm.
你好啊  孩子
Hey, buddy.
我能吃炒饭了吗
Can I have my fried rice?
当然  好  我们开吃吧
Yeah. Sure. Let's eat.
来
Come on.
这办公室也太临时了
The office looks very interim.
得要你进来嘛
I need to get you in here.
很高兴你来了
Hey. I'm really glad you came.
你今天去上学了吗
Did you, uh, get to school today?
我嗓子疼
I had a sore throat.
迈克尔  别玩了
Michael, not now.
迈克尔  把手机收起来
Michael, put your phone away.
我今天小胜了一回
So... I had a small victory.
埃利斯签署了命令让马克尔进了监狱
Ellis signed the order sending Maker to jail.
也是时候了
Oh. It's about time.
这个洁米·尼尔森什么事都要跟我争
This Jamie Nelson is gonna fight me on everything,
连审判室的室温也是
down to the temperature in the courtroom.
你应该把那家伙扔到油锅里
You should fry that kid.
是吗
Really?
为什么
And why's that?
因为他一无是处  对这个世界毫无价值
Because he's worthless. He adds no value to the world.
这就是你的看法吗
And that's your judgment?
-我们好好吃饭吧  -不  你
- Let's just have a nice dinner. - No. You -- you --
你不能轻易地就让别人去死
you don't just lightly send someone to their death.
你  你得把所有因素都考虑进来
You -- you consider everything involved.
才能做出明智的判断
You make an intelligent decision.
他杀了十八个学生  还需要判断吗
He killed 18 kids. What's the decision?
那是一条人命  迈克尔  我要对此负责的
It's someone's life, Michael, and I'm responsible for that.
我有我的责任
I have responsibilities.
如果你能走出你的房间
And if you got your ass out of your room
好好上学  你也会担起责任的
and got to school, you might appreciate that.
我们还是
Let's just...
抱歉  对不起
Sorry. I'm sorry.
肯定有问题
Well, it must be something.
那是家中餐馆
It's a Chinese restaurant.
难道说他们在餐馆后面种草药[大麻]吗
You saying they growing herb in the back of restaurants now?
我只知道那个西裔线人说那是合法的
Look, all I know is Criolla said it was legit.
那是苏格本人
It's Suger in the flesh.
这是怎么回事
What the hell is this?
这比我们应得的多
This is more than our cut.
这是那间温室全部的盈利
That's everything from the last house --
我们的全部盈利  洪兄弟
100% of our take, Brother Hong.
请你
And please...
向你们的老大转达我们对维克多·陈的悼念之情
give your boss our condolences about Victor Chan.
我是来弥补过错的
I'm here to make things right.
钱是不行的
The money's no good.
你懂我们的规矩
You know the rules.
我们要以血还血
We trade blood for blood.
这是唯一能消除后患的方法
It's the only way to avoid consequences.
杀死维克多·陈的男孩是贾利勒·汤普森
The boy who killed Victor Chan was Jalil Thompson.
他向条子认罪了  他偷了枪
He confessed to Five-o, took a piece.
现在被关在斯普鲁斯街的少管所里
Been down now for a few days over at Spruce Street Juvie.
他已经出了我们的势力范围  你们老大知道的
He's off our yard, man. Leadership knows.
做你该做的事
Do your work.
我们就扯平了
Then we even.
洪兄弟
Brother Hong.
走吧
Go.
你知道我们是一家人  对吧
You know that we're family, right,
我是你弟弟
that -- that I'm your brother?
天哪  你们不让我知道
Christ, it's -- it's bad enough
凯勒布死的真相就够不对的了
you keep me in the dark about Kaleb's murder,
你们现在竟然让我提供不在场证据
but then you ask me for a goddamn alibi?
你到底怎么了
I mean, what's the matter with you?
-你有不在场证据吗  -我还没说完她
- Do you have an alibi? - I'm not done with her.
-回答他  -你怎么不说说你自己
- Answer him. - Why don't you explain yourself?
凯勒布被杀那晚  我们在他的公寓里
We found your brand of whiskey at Kaleb's apartment
-找到了你喝的那个牌子的威士忌  -那又怎样
- The night he was killed. - So what?
你最近经常喝醉  很好斗
So you've been drunk lately, and you've been belligerent.
还有你的车库里为什么会有喷灯
And why do you have a blowtorch in your garage?
这是什么意思
What's that supposed to mean?
你  你觉得那是我杀人的凶器吗
Oh, you -- you think that's the smoking gun?
好吧  好吧  我承认
Okay, look, yeah, I-I confess.
我枪杀了他  然后布置了现场
I shot him, and then I doctored it up
造出了自杀的假象  天哪
to make it look like a suicide. Jesus christ!
不是吧  五分钟前  我还以为他是自杀
Really? Five minutes ago, I thought he killed himself,
你们俩都不给我一点时间让我
and you guys aren't even giving me a second here
-消化一下  -给我们不在场证据
- to process this. - Give us an alibi.
我们看了他的档案
We read his file,
你们俩  过去有矛盾
and, uh -- and you two have history.
那都是一年多以前了  只是吵架
That was over a year ago, and it was a scuffle.
我来告诉你们
Let me tell you something.
凯勒布和我关系非常好
Kaleb and I, we were tight.
他就像是我的兄弟
He was like a brother to me.
我失去了一个我真的很关心的人
I lost someone I genuinely cared about.
小麦  你当时在哪
Junior, where the hell were you?!
该死的  希尔蒂
God damn it, Hildy!
我当时跟别人在一起
I was with someone,
那个人不是玛丽
and it wasn't Mary.
我跟别的女人有婚外情了
I've been having an affair with another woman.
这就是  这就是我的大秘密  好吧
That's my -- that's my big secret, okay?
你高兴了
Are you happy?
她能证实你的话吗
Can she corroborate your story?
我们在市场街和第六大街的德文郡见的面
We meet up at the Devonshire on Market and 6th.
我去那是要跟她分手的
I was going there to break up with her.
如果你不相信我  你可以查一下
And if you don't believe me, you can check the security log
凯勒布死时那里的监控录像
at the time of Kaleb's death.
好吧  那这个姑娘
All right, what -- what -- what about this girl?
她叫什么名字
Does she -- does she have a name?
她叫阿莉莎
Her name's Alyssa.
你个混蛋
You're such an asshole.
冷静
Hey. Easy.
几点了
What time is it?
七点半
7:30.
天哪
Jesus.
我得走了  不过你想待到几点都行
I have to go, but you can stay as long as you want.
饿了的话  桌子上有早餐
And there's breakfast on the table if you're hungry.
有谁七点半就吃早餐
Who eats breakfast at 7:30?
昨晚让我非常难忘
Last night was pretty incredible for me.
我就是想告诉你  阿莉莎
I just want to say that, Alyssa.
亲爱的阿莉莎
Oh, sweet Alyssa.
天哪
Oh, boy.
你们俩真漂亮
You two look gorgeous.
你也是  玛丽
You, too, Mary.
-斯蒂芙  你怎么样  -很好
- Hey, Steff. How's it going? - Good.
你能帮我把礼物放过去吗
Can you drop the gift over there for me?
-好的  -谢谢  宝贝
- Yeah. -  Thanks, babe.
我以前从来没来过这种场合  挺有意思的
I've never been to one of these before. Looks like so much fun.
是啊  当然了
Yeah. Absolutely.
家人团聚真好
Nice to have the family together.
是啊
For sure.
我去拿点喝的  一会儿见
Let me grab a drink. I'll see you in a bit.
介绍一下我的朋友阿莉莎
I want to introduce my friend Alyssa.
你好  很高兴见到你
Hi. Nice to meet you.
你好  阿莉莎  我也很高兴见到你
Hi, Alyssa. Nice to meet you, too.
我去拿杯喝的
Uh, I'm gonna grab a drink.
-好  你真漂亮  -谢谢  你也很帅
- Great. You look great. - Oh, thanks. You, too.
-你很美  -谢谢  你也很帅
- You look nice. - Thank you. You, too.
想谈谈工作上的事吗
You want to talk about work?
不是吧
Oh, no.
我们还需要再调查一个人
We got one more person that still needs to check out,
但现在不是时候
but right now is probably not the time.
-那是纳瓦罗的弟弟吗  -对
- Is that Navarro's brother? - Yeah.
蹲了几年牢真是改变了他很多啊
Wow. Prison put some years on him, huh?
是啊  还搞了这么多纹身
Yeah. And some ink.
我去跟他打声招呼  行吧
I'm gonna go check him out. You good?
行  一会见
Yeah, I'm good. See you in a bit.
露易丝  不是吧
Louise. Really?
居然吃糖  不行
With the sugar? No.
-别吃了  -听你妈妈的话
- You got to stop, please. - Listen to your mom.
听到他说的了吧
Yeah, what he said.
再准备你一会的讲话吗
Going over your speech?
是啊  要讲话  还要跳舞
Ha. My speech, uh, my dance,
正在努力不现在就紧张到出汗
trying not to sweat right now.
是不是一直想着办这么一场派对
Probably thinking about that second mortgage you have to
你得要二次抵押多少
take out to afford all this, huh?
兄弟  而且我还得再这样弄三回
And I got to do it three more times, homey.
为啥我就不能生个男孩
I couldn't have had one boy?
我也刚想说这个
I was just gonna say that.
不过我还是很感谢你办了派对
I appreciate you doing this, though, for real.
这一周很难熬
It's been a tough week.
凯勒布自杀这事...
The thing that happened with Kaleb...
大家都难以接受
difficult for everybody to swallow.
我不这么觉得
Not for me.
你这是什么意思
What do you mean by that?
就是我说的字面意思
Exactly what I said.
你什么时候开始讨厌凯勒布了
Since when do you not like Kaleb?
听着  泰瑞
Know what, Terry?
老实说
To tell the truth...
我今天一点也不想谈论这件事
this is the last thing I want to talk about today.
明天我们再想谈多久谈多久吧
Tomorrow, we can kick it all day if you want.
干杯
Cheers.
恭喜
Congrats.
我...有点紧张
Um, I'm a little nervous. Um...
安娜  你已经长大
So, Anna, as you go out into the world
迈进了成年世界
as a young lady,
我想让你知道  我爱你
I want you to know I love you.
你永远是我的心肝宝贝
You'll always be in my heart.
无论发生什么
And no matter what happens,
我永远都在你身边
su padre siempre estará contigo.
干杯
Salud!
我的女儿  各位
My daughter, everyone.
这是干嘛  要煞威风吗
What is this, a beatdown?
-那就来吧  -不是煞威风
- Bring it! - This ain't no beatdown.
是为了替维克多·陈报仇
This is payback for Victor Chan.
维克多·陈
Victor Chan?!
血债血偿  贱人
Blood for blood, bitch.
不是我  我没有杀你的人
Wasn't me! I ain't the one who killed your boy!
是柯麦佳  我对天发誓
It was Kormega! I swear on my ma!
是柯麦佳杀了他
Kormega's the one who did him.
卡尔·麦金尼斯被杀一案
The homicide of Carl Mcginness, a human being,
帕姆·史蒂文斯被杀一案
the homicide of Pam Stevens, a human being,
桑德拉·达菲被杀一案
the homicide of Sandra Duffy, a human being,
赫克特·维拉斯奎兹被杀一案
the homicide of Hector Velazquez, a human being,
以及克雷格·斯潘瑟被杀一案
and the homicide of Craig Spether, a human being --
马克尔先生  你是否清楚你所受到的这些指控
Mr. Maker, do you understand the charges brought against you?
是的  法官阁下
Yes, Your Honor.
很好  检方希望本次庭审如何进行
Very well. And the prosecution? How would you like to proceed?
法庭应当审查为适用于死刑判决所必需的
The court will be seeking special circumstances
各种特定情形  法官阁下
necessary for capital punishment, Your Honor.
辩方的陈述意见呢
How does the defense plead?
马克尔先生对各项指控均愿意表示认罪
Mr. Maker wishes to enter a plea of guilty on all accounts.
你能再说一遍吗  尼尔森女士
Would you repeat that, Ms. Nelson?
法官阁下  马克尔先生此刻承认所有指控事实
Your Honor, Mr. Maker accepts all of the allegations
及其修正内容  并认可被控罪名
and enhancements at this time and pleads guilty as charged.
我是穆里根
Mulligan.
什么事
Yeah, what's this about?
什么
What?
什么时候
When?
好  我马上到  我这就来
Okay, yeah, I'll be there soon. I'm on my way.
他妈在吗
Is his mom there?
好  我应该作为在场警官  所以...
Okay. Yeah, no, I should be the officer present, so...
多谢你打来  非常感谢
Thanks for the call. I appreciate it.
再见
Okay, bye.
希尔蒂
Hildy?
贾利勒·汤普森在少管所内被杀
Jalil Thompson was murdered in juvie,
但我觉得根本就不会对此立案吧
but I guess that was just a nothing case, right?
尽快结束吧
Let's get this over with.
那是你儿子吗  女士
Is that your son, ma'am?
是
Yes, it is.
你是来让我节哀的吗
You here to say sorry?
嗯
Yeah.
然后呢
Then what?
回到自己家
You go back home?
看到自己的孩子
To see your kids?
你有孩子吧
You got kids?
我有个女儿
I have a daughter, yeah.
好
Good.
你回到自己家
You go back to your house,
将自己的女儿搂在怀中
and you hold your daughter in your arms.
你紧紧抱住她
You squeeze her tight
告诉她
and tell her
一切都会好起来的
everything is gonna be all right.
然后你想到你怎么害死了我的儿子
Then you think about how you killed my son...
我的天使
my angel.
我没有别人了
I got no one left.
那小兄弟死了
Nigga's dead.
我们没事
We good.
死了个兄弟怎么会没事
There ain't nothing good about a dead nigga.
如果能阻止战争那就没事
There is if it stops a war.
你说得没错
You right.
我会告诉他妈妈的
I'll go talk to his moms.
她是我们的家人了
She's ours now.
她由我们照顾了
She's our responsibility.
当然了
No doubt.
你还好吧
You good?
只是今晚
For tonight.
暴风雨就要来了
But a storm's coming.